Guide to the Harry Scherman Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Cataloged Correspondence and Manuscripts
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 20 Feb 1952 to Harry Scherman, (a.p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 5 May 1952 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 28 Sept 1952 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 2 p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 15 March 1953 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. London, 15 October 1953 to Harry Scherman and Meredith Wood, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. 1957 – 1965 carbon copies of letters and miscellaneous material relating to Morley and the Morley Memorial (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, N.Y., 8 August [1950]; to Amy Loveman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Helen (Mrs. ChristopherRoslyn Heights, June 1957 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 2p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Helen (Mrs. ChristopherRoslyn Heights, 18 October 1957 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Moses, Robert. New York, 7 Nov 1942 to Christopher Morley, (t.l.s. 1p. Original enclosed with Morley, Christopher, New York, 9 Nov. 1942, To Harry Scherman, t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Nash, Ogden. Baltimore, 11 Dec 1966 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 4p.) (Box 6)
  - Nathan, George Jean. New York, 1 Jan 1956 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s., 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Reynal, Eugene. New York, 15 April 1949 Telegram to John Marquand. (Box 6)
  - Roosvelt, Eleanor (Mrs. Franklin DelanoNew York, 10 Oct 1949 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Salmen, Stanley. Boston, 19 July 1949 to John Marquand, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Scherman, Harry. n.p. 1948 to Henry Seidel Canby, (a.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Scherman, Harry. New York, 14 July 1954 to Henry Seidel Canby, (t.l.s. 1p) (Box 6)
  - Scott, Cecil. New York, 5 Nov 1965 to Clifton Fadiman, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Sloane, William. New York, 21 June 1954 to Harry Scherman (Box 6)
  - Steinbeck, John. Sag Harbor, 6 Nov 1962 to Harry Scherman; p.c.s. (Box 6)
  - Stettinius, Edward R., Jr. New York, 21 Sept 1938 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Stevenson, Adlai E. New York, 9 Feb 1962 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Stoller, Mollie. New York, 9 Feb 1962 to Clifton Fadiman, (t.l.s., 1p) (Box 6)
  - Also, Fadiman, Clifton, [New York, May, 1949], to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s., 1p. appended to the above) (Box 6)
  - Streit, Clarence K. New York, 29 Feb 1940 to Christopher Morley, (t.l.s. 2p.) (Box 6)
  - Tarbell, Ida M. Bethel, Conn, 24 Nov 1941 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 2p) (Box 6)
  - Thornhill, Arthur H. Boston, 22 June 1954 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Truman, Harry S. Kansas City, Mo., 22 Nov 1955 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Truman, Harry S. Kansas City, Mo., 21 Jan 1956 to Harry Scherman, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Tuchman, Barbara. New York, 13 Dec 1961 to Clifton Fadiman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem. Old Greenwich, Conn. 30 March 1933 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Walk, Henry Z. New York, 18 June 1954 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Walsh, Richard J. New York, 18 June 1954 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Weizmann, Chain. n.p. 7 November 1951 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Welles, Sumner. Washington, 24 April 1943. to Henry Seidel Canby, (1p. (signed by Anna L. Clarkson, ass’t to Welles); t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - White, Sallie L. (Mrs. William A.Emporia, Kansas City, 14 Dec 1943 to Harry and Bernadine Scherman, (a.l.s. 4p. with envelope) (Box 6)
  - White, Sallie L. (Mrs. William A.Emporia, Kansas City, 15 Jan 1944 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 7p. with envelope) (Box 6)
  - White, Sallie L. (Mrs. William A.Emporia, Kansas City, 20 Oct 1944 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 3p.) (Box 6)
  - White, Sallie L. (Mrs. William A.Emporia, Kansas City, ca March 1944 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - White, Sallie L. (Mrs. William A.Emporia, Kansas City, 20 March 1944 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 4p.) (Box 6)
  - White, Sallie L. (Mrs. William A.Emporia, Kansas City, 13 April 1944 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - White, Sallie L. (Mrs. William A.Emporia, Kansas City, ca. Feb 1945 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 2p.) (Box 6)
  - White, William Allen. [Emporia], 1944 – 1945 To Walter Lippmann, (t.l. 3p. copy) (Box 6)
  - White, William Allen. V.p., 1938 – 1943 To Harry Scherman, (58 t.l.s. and 1 telegram) (Box 6)
  - White, William Allen. Carbon Copies of Harry Scherman’s letters to White, 1938 – 1944 92 telegrams, 1938 – 1943., (168 items, also includes misc. material) (Box 6)
  - White, William Allen. Carbon copies of Harry Scherman’s letters to White. 1938-1940., (57 items.) (Box 6)
  - White, William Allen. Carbon copies of Harry Scherman’s letters to White. 1941-1942., (64 items) (Box 6)
  - White, William Allen. Carbon copies of Harry Scherman’s letters to White. 1943-1944., (28 items.) (Box 6)
  - White, William Allen. Carbon copies of letters and miscellaneous material relating to White or The White Memorial. 1939-1944., (19 items) (Box 6)
  - Wolff, Helen (Mrs. KurtNew York, 9 July 1947 To Harry Scherman, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wood, Meredith. n.p., n.d. & 1950. To John Marquand., (1 telegram, copy and 1 cablegram copy) (Box 6)
  - Young, Owen D. New York, 18 Jan 1948. To Harry Scherman, (signed by his secretary; with carbon copy of related letter from Scherman), (1 p. t.l.) (Box 6)
  - Zock, George Washington, 20 Jan 1948 To Harry Scherman, with carbon copy of related letter from Scherman, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 6)
- Series III: Material by and about Harry Scherman
  - Publications and reviews of books (Box 7)
  - Awards and letters of appreciation (Box 7)
  - Book-of-Month-Club: articles, clippings, pamphlets, subsidiary organizations (Box 7)
  - Personal items (Box 8)
  - Book of Press Agent Clippings (Box 8)
  - Photographs (Box 8)
  - Bank Street College Memoranda (Box 8)
- Series IV: Topical Files
  - Atlantic Congress (Box 9)
  - Atlantic Council (Box 9)
  - Atlantic Union Committee (Box 9)
  - Atlantic Unity, Declaration of (Box 9)
  - Federal Union, Inc. (Box 10)
  - Correspondence with Clarence K. Streit, reports, papers, 1948-1966 (Box 10)
  - Committee on Economic Development (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, reports, etc. 1942 – 1964 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence (uncatalogedand miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - “Promises Men Live By” – notes and drafts (Box 13)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research – papers, correspondence, reports; 1939-1964 (Box 14)
  - “Promises Men Live By” (Box 15)
  - Printers copy (Box 15)
  - Correspondence and clippings (Box 15)
  - “Promises Men Live By” (Box 16)
  - Typescript, proofs, book and miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - “Promises Men Live By” (Box 17)
  - Autograph manuscript (Box 17)
  - Corrected carbon of chapter 1-8 (Box 17)
  - Harry Scherman’s papers (Box 18)
  - “Promises Men Live By” Typescript (Box 18)
  - Harry Scherman’s papers (Box 19)
  - “Promises Men Live By” (Box 19)
  - Typescript (Box 19)
- Series V: Arranged Correspondence
  - A (Box 20)
  - B-Benton (Box 21)
  - Benton (continued)-By (Box 22)
  - C-Cha (Box 23)
  - Che-Con (Box 24)
  - Cou-Do (Box 25)
  - Du (Box 26)
  - F-Fe (Box 27)
  - Fi-Fisher (Box 28)
  - Fisher (continued)-G (Box 29)
  - H-He (Box 30)
  - Hi-I (Box 31)
  - J-Le (Box 32)
  - Li-Lo (Box 33)
  - M-Man (Box 34)
  - Mar-Mu (Box 35)
  - N-Nec (Box 36)
  - New-O (Box 37)
  - Publishers Correspondence (Box 38-42)
  - P-Sa (Box 43)
  - Sch (Box 44)
  - Si-Sl (Box 45)
  - Sm-V (Box 46)
  - V-Wi (Box 47)
  - Wo-Z (Box 48)
- Series VI: Printed Material
  - Printed material (Box 49)